Carolina Power and Light Photograph Collection PHC.68
State Archives of North Carolina
- Raleigh, NC, Night View of Fayetteville Street Looking South c. 1949. Night view of Fayetteville Street looking south from Capitol in Raleigh, NC. Few cars are seen parked along the street with no pedestrians. Various businesses are seen. Raleigh, Wake County, NC c. 1949, PhC.68.1.136; Carolina Power and Light
- Raleigh, NC, Elevated Night View of Fayetteville Street Looking North c. 1949. Elevated night view of Fayetteville Street from the top of the Wake County Courthouse in Raleigh, NC. Light trails from passing cars are seen on Fayetteville street as streetlights illuminate the buildings and street. Raleigh, Wake County, NC c. 1949, PhC.68.1.137; Carolina Power and Light
- Raleigh, NC, Fayetteville Street Looking South From Martin Street at Night c. 1950. Night view of Fayetteville Street its intersection with Martin Street in Raleigh, NC, looking south. Automobiles are seen parked along the sides of the street, businesses are seen including, Martin's, Western Union, and Hudson Belk. The Durham Life Insurance Building is seen on the right. Raleigh, Wake County, NC c. 1950., PhC.68.1.138; Carolina Power and Light
- Raleigh, NC, Night View of Fayetteville Street Looking South c. 1961. Elevated night view of Fayetteville Street seen from the top of the Capitol Dome looking south. The street is seen illuminated by streetlights and automobiles. Raleigh, Wake County, NC c. 1961, PhC.68.1.139.1-2; Carolina Power and Light
- Raleigh, NC, Elevated Night View of Fayetteville Street Looking North c. 1962. Elevated night view of Fayetteville Street in Raleigh, NC. Possibly taken from the Durham Life Insurance Building looking north towards the NC Capitol. The street is pictured lined with shops and parked automobiles. A rain has recently fallen creating wet streets. Raleigh, Wake County, NC c. 1962, PhC.68.1.140; Carolina Power and Light
- Raleigh, NC, Fayetteville Street Looking North from Cabarrus Street c.1962. Night view of Fayetteville street at Cabarrus Street looking north. Automobiles are seen parked along the street as streetlights illuminate the area. Various businesses are seen including Thompson Cadillac, Pep Boys, Hardbarger Business College, Hotel Sir Walter and Firestone. Raleigh, Wake County, NC c. 1962, PhC.68.1.141.1-2; Carolina Power and Light
- Raleigh, NC, West Side of Fayetteville Street Looking North Toward Capitol c. 1962. Night view of the west side of Fayetteville Street looking north from Woolworths. People are seen walking down side walks past illuminated store windows. Automobiles are parked along Fayetteville street as streetlights illuminate the area. Raleigh, Wake County, NC c. 1962, PhC.68.1.142; Carolina Power and Light
- Raleigh, NC, Night View of Fayetteville and Hargett Streets Intersection c. 1949. Night view of Hargett Street at its intersection with Fayetteville Street looking west. Walgreen Drug is seen on the left in the Raleigh Building. Little activity on street, few automobiles seen. Raleigh, Wake County, NC c. 1949, PhC.68.1.143; Carolina Power and Light
- Raleigh, NC, East Martin Street Looking West c. 1917. Night view of Martin Street looking West from Wilmington Street. Street lights illuminate the area. Two automobiles are seen parked on the street. A streetcar line runs down the center of the street. Raleigh, Wake County, NC c. 1917, PhC.68.1.144; Carolina Power and Light
- Raleigh, NC, Martin Street Looking East From Fayetteville Street c. 1949. Night view of the intersection of Fayetteville and Martin Streets looking east. The entrance and south side of the bottom floors of Citizens National Bank at the NE corner of the intersection is seen. Mecca Diner can be seen in the distance, down Martin Street along with other businesses. Raleigh, Wake County, NC c. 1949, PhC.68.1.145; Carolina Power and Light
- Raleigh, NC, Elevated Night View of Martin Street West from Fayetteville Street c.1919. Elevated night view of Martin Street in Raleigh, NC looking west from the Commercial National Bank. Various downtown buildings are seen including, Capital Club building, The Bland Hotel, and Century Post Office. Raleigh, Wake County, NC 1919, PhC.68.1.146; Carolina Power and Light
- Raleigh, NC, Night View of West Martin Street Looking East c.1920. Night view of Martin Street looking east in Raleigh, NC. Strand Theatre, Dillon Supply and other businesses are seen as streetlights illuminate area. Raleigh, Wake County, NC c. 1920, PhC.68.1.147; Carolina Power and Light
- Raleigh, NC, Elevated View Looking South Over City c. 1918. Elevated view looking south over the city of Raleigh, NC. Likely taken from the top of the Raleigh water tower on Hargett Street. Citizens National Bank, Raleigh Industrial Bank, Commercial National Bank, various downtown buildings, residences, and gardens are seen. Raleigh, Wake County, NC c. 1918, PhC.68.1.148; Carolina Power and Light
- Raleigh, NC, Aerial View of Fayetteville Street Looking North c. 1924. Aerial view looking north from Memorial Auditorium. Fayetteville Street is seen from the air with the State Capitol Building at the top of the street. Sir Walter Hotel, Lawyers Building, Citizen National Bank, Raleigh Building and other various downtown buildings and businesses are seen. Raleigh, Wake County, NC c. 1924, PhC.68.1.149.1-2; Carolina Power and Light
- Raleigh, NC, Aerial View Looking North c.1949. Wide aerial view of the entire downtown area in Raleigh, NC. Shows undeveloped and industrial areas on outskirts along with developed areas in the center of town. Raleigh, Wake County, NC c. 1949, PhC.68.1.150.1-2; Carolina Power and Light
- Raleigh, NC, Aerial View of Downtown c. 1966. Aerial view of downtown Raleigh, NC business district. Salisbury, Fayetteville and Wilmington Streets are seen looking north toward Capitol. Raleigh, Wake County, NC c. 1966, PhC.68.1.151; Carolina Power and Light
- Raleigh, NC, Edenton Street Residential Area Looking West c. 1928. Pictured is the 700 block of East Edenton Street in Raleigh, NC. Sidewalk and street are seen looking west. Present day Cooke Street intersection is seen in near background. Raleigh, Wake County, NC c. 1928, PhC.68.1.152; Carolina Power and Light
- Raleigh, NC, Corner of Davie and Fayetteville Streets Looking South c. 1920. Corner of Fayetteville and Davie Streets looking south. A small girl is seen walking down the sidewalk and a street car is seen traveling north on Fayetteville Street. Workmen are seen working between the sidewalk and the street. Residence of Governor Fowle is just out of frame on the right. Previously identified as "residential s11t. possibly Hillsborough" Raleigh, Wake County, NC c. 1920, PhC.68.1.153; Carolina Power and Light
- Raleigh, NC, Fayetteville and Davie Streets, Governor Fowle Residence c. 1920. Pictured is the corner of Fayetteville and Davie Streets in Raleigh, NC. The residence of Governor Daniel Fowle can be seen behind trees. Raleigh, Wake County, NC c. 1920. Previously identified as, "Ground- Level Street Scene View of an Unidentified Residence, Probably at Raleigh, Wake County, North Carolina; Photograph Taken circa 1920.", PhC.68.1.154; Carolina Power and Light
- Raleigh, NC, Various Street Scenes in Downtown c. 1942., PhC.68.1.155; Carolina Power and Light
  - Raleigh, NC, Various Street Scenes in Downtown c. 1942. PhC68.1.155.1 -Intersection of Hargett and Fayetteville Streets in Raleigh, NC looking southeast. Busses, cars and pedestrians are seen. c. 1942, PhC.68.1.155.1; Carolina Power and Light
  - Hargett Street looking west from Wilmington Street is seen. Various businesses are seen. Cars are parked on the street as a pedestrian crosses the street. The Raleigh Building is seen on left in near background. c. 1942, PhC.68.1.155.2; Carolina Power and Light
  - Wilmington Street looking south from Morgan Street is seen. Various businesses are seen including Hill's Harley Davidson, Bamby Bread Company and Wake Cafe. c. 1942, PhC.68.1.155.3; Carolina Power and Light
  - Intersection of Martin and Fayetteville Streets looking northeast at the entrance to Citizens National Bank. Busses, cars and trucks are seen on the street along with pedestrians and various businesses. c. 1942, PhC.68.1.155.4; Carolina Power and Light
  - Intersection of Morgan and Fayetteville Streets looking east. A pedestrian, cars and busses are seen. c. 1942, PhC.68.1.155.5; Carolina Power and Light
  - Hargett Street looking east from approximately 20 Hargett Street. Pedestrians, cars and trucks are seen. The north side of the Raleigh Building is seen including Bowman's Jewelers. c. 1942, PhC.68.1.155.6; Carolina Power and Light
  - Intersection of Morgan and Salisbury looking east. Busses and cars are seen on the street. c. 1942, PhC.68.1.155.7; Carolina Power and Light
  - 100 block of Wilmington Street looking north. Cars are seen in the street and various businesses are seen. c. 1942, PhC.68.1.155.8; Carolina Power and Light
  - Fayetteville Street is seen looking south from Capitol grounds. A man is seen walking toward camera up the steps to the capitol grounds. Various buildings and businesses are seen. (no copy negative) c. 1942, PhC.68.1.155.9; Carolina Power and Light
  - A horse drawn Raleigh Streetcar replica is pictured in the 1940's with people dressed in early 1900s fashion. (no copy negative) c. 1942, PhC.68.1.155.10; Carolina Power and Light
  - Wilmington Street looking south from Morgan Street is seen. Various businesses are seen including Hill's Harley Davidson, Bamby Bread Company and Wake Cafe. c. 1942, PhC.68.1.155.11; Carolina Power and Light
  - Intersection of Martin and Fayetteville Streets in Raleigh, NC looking north. Century post office can be seen at extreme left. A US Marines recruit poster can be seen in front of the post office. c. 1942, PhC.68.1.155.12; Carolina Power and Light
  - PhC68.1.155.13 -Fayetteville Street is seen looking south from Capitol grounds. A woman is seen walking away from camera toward Fayetteville Street. Various buildings and businesses are seen. c. 1942, PhC.68.1.155.13; Carolina Power and Light
  - Intersection of Morgan and Fayetteville Streets in Raleigh, NC looking east. A man and woman are seen walking together headed west on Morgan Street. c. 1942, PhC.68.1.155.14; Carolina Power and Light
  - Morgan Street in Raleigh, NC looking west. Cars are seen lining and traveling in both directions down the street. The Ruffin Building and Justice Building are both seen on the left. (no copy negative) c. 1942, PhC.68.1.155.15; Carolina Power and Light
- Raleigh, NC, Oddfellows Building c. 1940. The Oddfellows Building is pictured at the corner of Salisbury and Hargett Streets in Raleigh, NC. At extreme right the corner of the Raleigh Industrial Bank is also seen. Various businesses are seen in the bottom of the Oddfellows Building including, Hollywood Lunches, Bowman's Jewelers, McLeod and Watson, and Efird's Department Store. Raleigh, Wake County, NC c. 1940, PhC.68.1.156; Carolina Power and Light
- Raleigh, NC, Davie Street Looking West From Salisbury Street c. 1964. Three CP&L workers are seen on the sidewalk of Davie Street. View looking west. Power lines are seen dangling down near men. Raleigh, Wake County, NC c. 1964, PhC.68.1.157; Carolina Power and Light
- Raleigh, NC, West Davie Street c. 1964. View looking west on Davie Street at CP&L workers gathered on the sidewalk. Intersection of Davie and McDowell can be seen in background. c. summer 1964, PhC.68.1.158; Carolina Power and Light
- Raleigh, NC, Men Working on West Davie Street c. 1964. A small group of men are seen gathered at a construction site next to a Volkswagen Beetle on West Davie Street. Raleigh, Wake County, NC c. summer 1964, PhC.68.1.159; Carolina Power and Light
- Raleigh, NC, Raleigh Ice and Storage Company c. 1923. Exterior view from street of Raleigh Ice and Storage Company on West Hargett Street in Raleigh, NC. An automobile and several men can be seen on the left side of the picture. Raleigh, Wake County, NC c. 1924, PhC.68.1.160.1-2; Carolina Power and Light
- Raleigh, NC, Boylan Apartments c. 1930. Western side of Boylan Apartments is pictured with automobiles pictured parked along Snow Avenue in Raleigh, NC. View from site of present day Cameron Court Apartments. Raleigh, Wake County, NC c. 1, PhC.68.1.161.1-2; Carolina Power and Light
- Raleigh, NC, Night View of North Carolina Capitol Building c. 1930. Close night view of the west side of the North Carolina Capitol Building. Lights are seen illuminating side of building. c. 1930's, PhC.68.1.162; Carolina Power and Light
- Raleigh, NC, Capitol Building From Northeast c. 1921. Eastern side of the North Carolina Capitol Building. Automobiles can be seen parked on right side of the building. Raleigh, Wake County, NC c. 1921, PhC.68.1.163; Carolina Power and Light
- Raleigh, NC, Zeb Vance Statue, Floodlights at NC Capitol c.1928. Two view of newly installed floodlights at the NC Capitol. One view down New Bern Ave and another of the west side of the building showing the lights. Governor Zebulon B. Vance statue can be seen in the picture depicting New Bern Avenue c. 1928, PhC.68.1.164.1-3; Carolina Power and Light
- Raleigh, NC, Capitol Building From Southeast, Raleigh, ca. 1958. View of the eastern and northern side of the State Capitol Building in Raleigh. Raleigh, Wake County, NC c. 1958, PhC.68.1.165.1-2; Carolina Power and Light
- Raleigh, NC, Interior View of Senate Chamber in Legislative Building c. 1963. Interior view of the Senate chamber in the Legislative Building in Raleigh, NC c. 1963, PhC.68.1.166; Carolina Power and Light
- Raleigh, NC, Governor's Mansion Shown at Night c. 1966. Governor's Mansion is pictured from southwest side at night in Raleigh, NC c. January 1966, PhC.68.1.167; Carolina Power and Light
- Raleigh, NC, Artists Rendering of Durham Life Insurance Building November 1942., PhC.68.1.168; Carolina Power and Light
- Raleigh, NC, Sir Walter Hotel and Durham Life Insurance Building c. 1944. View looking south on Fayetteville Street in Raleigh, NC. The Sir Walter Hotel and Durham Life Insurance Building are both seen with cars parked in front on the street. The old Wake County Courthouse is seen on extreme right. Raleigh, Wake County, NC c. 1944, PhC.68.1.169; Carolina Power and Light
- Raleigh, NC, Durham Life Insurance Building, Davie and Fayetteville Streets c.1950. Corner of Davie and Fayetteville Streets in Raleigh, NC. The Durham Life Insurance Building is seen on the corner. Raleigh Diner sign is seen in foreground with electric lines running above. Raleigh, Wake County, NC c. 1950, PhC.68.1.170; Carolina Power and Light
- Raleigh, NC, Hotel Sir Walter and Durham Life Insurance Building c. 1950. Elevated view of the Durham Life Insurance building from the back side (Salisbury Street). Hotel Sir Walter and the Wake County Courthouse can also be seen. Raleigh, Wake County, NC c. 1950, PhC.68.1.171; Carolina Power and Light
- Raleigh, NC, Revenue Building, Salisbury and Morgan Streets c. 1930. The Revenue Building in Raleigh, NC is pictured from the corner of Morgan and Salisbury streets. Cars are seen parked on all sides of the street. Raleigh, Wake County, NC c. 1930, PhC.68.1.172; Carolina Power and Light
- Raleigh, NC, Capital Apartments c. 1925. View of Capital Apartments on the corner of Blount Street and New Bern Avenue in Raleigh, NC. c. 1925, PhC.68.1.173; Carolina Power and Light
- Raleigh, NC, Dorothea Dix State Hospital for Insane c.1910. Rear view of the Dorothea Dix campus c. 1910. Raleigh, Wake County, PhC.68.1.174; Carolina Power and Light
- Raleigh, NC, Carolina Power and Light Offices, Raleigh Banking and Trust c. 1913. Southeastern corner of Fayetteville and Hargett Streets showing the Raleigh Banking and Trust building. Carolina Power and Light occupied this building for their offices. Pedestrians are seen on the sidewalks and cars are seen parked on the sides of the streets. Raleigh, Wake County, NC c. 1913, PhC.68.1.175.1-2; Carolina Power and Light
- Raleigh, NC, Crowd Gathers At Raleigh Banking and Trust c. 1925. A crowd of formally dressed people are seen gathered and funneling into the front doors of the Carolina Power and Light Offices in the Raleigh Banking and Trust Building on Fayetteville Street in Raleigh, NC. Cars are seen parked on street. Efird's Department Store is seen on the left. Raleigh, Wake County, NC c. 1925, PhC.68.1.176.1-2; Carolina Power and Light
- Raleigh, NC, Capital Club Building Martin and Salisbury Streets. Raleigh, N.C., 1933. Elevated view of the Capital Club building at the Corner of Martin and Salisbury Streets in downtown Raleigh, NC. Citizens National Bank is seen in the background on right along with other businesses along the streets. Raleigh, Wake County, NC c. 1948, PhC.68.1.177; Carolina Power and Light
- Raleigh, NC, Agricultural and Mechanical College, NC State c. 1909. View looking west on Hillsborough Street at intersection with present day Horne Street. Tompkins hall is seen along with Pullen Hall, Holladay Hall, Brooks Hall and others. A small railroad (streetcar?) is seen running along the north side of present day Hillsborough Street. Raleigh, Wake County, NC 15 May 1909, PhC.68.1.178.1-2; Carolina Power and Light
- Raleigh, NC, Holladay Hall, NC State c. 1909. Exterior view of Holladay Hall at North Carolina State University. The building is surrounded by dirt roads/paths and is mostly covered in ivy. Raleigh, Wake County, NC c. 1909, PhC.68.1.179; Carolina Power and Light
- Raleigh, NC, Aerial View, NC State Looking East c. 1968. Aerial view looking east of the North Campus of North Carolina State University in Raleigh. Many buildings can be identified including, Harrelson Hall, Tompkins Hall, Winston Hall, Peele Hall, Holladay Hall, Leazar, Brooks, Harrelson Hall, Winslow Hall, 1911, the Bell Tower and others. Raleigh, Wake County, NC c. 1968, PhC.68.1.180; Carolina Power and Light
- Raleigh, NC, St. Mary's College, c. 1909 and 1920s-30s. Two images of Saint Mary's College Campus seen from Hillsborough Street. One image is c. 1909, the other image is c. 1920s-30s. Raleigh, Wake County, NC, PhC.68.1.181.1-2; Carolina Power and Light
- Raleigh, NC, Peace College, Raleigh, N. C., 1926. Two views of Peace College in Raleigh, NC. One wide view from distance shows main building and several others. Second image is a close view of the front of the main building. Raleigh, Wake County, NC c. 1926, PhC.68.1.182.1-2; Carolina Power and Light
- Raleigh, NC, Baptist University for Women (Meredith College) c. 1909. Exterior view of Baptist University for Women on Blount Street in Raleigh, NC. One automobile is seen parked in the driveway in front of the building. Raleigh, Wake County, NC c. 1909, PhC.68.1.183; Carolina Power and Light
- Raleigh, NC, Meredith College, Hillsborough Street ca. 1930. Exterior View of the main building on the Hillsborough Street campus of Meredith College. Raleigh, Wake County, NC c. 1930, PhC.68.1.184; Carolina Power and Light
- Raleigh, NC, City Hall and Auditorium, Fayetteville Street c. 1947. Front of City Hall and Auditorium on the corner of Fayetteville and Davie Streets in Raleigh, NC. Cars are seen parked in front of the building on Fayetteville Street. Pedestrians are seen on the sidewalk. Raleigh, Wake County, NC c. 1947, PhC.68.1.185; Carolina Power and Light
- Raleigh, NC, Mary Elizabeth Hospital c. 1930. Exterior view of Mary Elizabeth Hospital at 1100 Wake Forest Road in Raleigh, NC. Wake County c. 1930, PhC.68.1.186; Carolina Power and Light
- Raleigh, NC, Broughton High School c. 1936. Exterior view of Broughton High School from distance showing the entire front of the school and a section of undeveloped Peace Street. Raleigh, Wake County, NC c. 1936, PhC.68.1.187.1-2; Carolina Power and Light
- Raleigh, NC, Workers Installing Streetcar Tracks on East Lane Street c. 1916. Western facing view of work crew on East Lane Street installing street car rail. Workers are seen in road setting brick and rail. Others are seen on sides of road. One African American man is seen sitting in a horse drawn wagon with Harley Davidson advertising. What appears to be a job foreman is seen on right side of frame wearing a uniform and a hat. Raleigh, Wake County, NC 6 June 1916 **Previously identified as "Paving of East Lane Street"., PhC.68.1.188.1-2; Carolina Power and Light
- Raleigh, NC, Hotel Carolina, c. 1930. Hotel Raleigh is seen on the corner of Dawson and Hargett Streets in Raleigh, NC. Streetcar lines and automobiles are seen. Raleigh, Wake County, NC c. 1930, PhC.68.1.189; Carolina Power and Light
- Raleigh, NC, Sir Walter Hotel c. 1930. Elevated view of east and north sides of Hotel Sir Walter on the corner of Fayetteville and Davie Streets in Raleigh, NC. Cars are seen parked on the sides of the streets. Raleigh, Wake County, NC c. 1930, PhC.68.1.190.1-3; Carolina Power and Light
- Raleigh, NC, Henry Clay Oak Tree c. 1965. Three views of the Henry Clay Oak Tree on North street in Raleigh, NC. The A. B. Andrews House is seen in the background. Raleigh, Wake County, NC c. 1965, PhC.68.1.191.1-3; Carolina Power and Light
- Raleigh, NC, State Penitentiary, 15 May 1909. View looking south from Morgan Street of State Penitentiary in Raleigh, NC. View shows entire length of building from a medium distance. Raleigh, Wake County, NC, 15 May 1909, PhC.68.1.192; Carolina Power and Light
- Raleigh, NC, Memorial Auditorium c. 1932. Front exterior view of Raleigh Memorial Auditorium. Raleigh, Wake County, NC c. 1932, PhC.68.1.193.1-2; Carolina Power and Light
- Raleigh, NC, Wake County Courthouse c. 1926. Elevated exterior view of the Wake County courthouse in Raleigh, NC. c. 1926, PhC.68.1.194.1-2; Carolina Power and Light
- Raleigh, NC, Andrew Johnson Birthplace, Cabarrus Street c. 1920. Front exterior view of the Andrew Johnson Birthplace in Raleigh, NC as it appeared on Cabarrus Street. Raleigh, Wake County, NC c. 1920, PhC.68.1.195; Carolina Power and Light
- Raleigh, NC, Aerials of Halifax Court Housing Project c. 1939. Three aerial views of Halifax Court Housing Project. Two photographs from different angles and one artists rendering are included. Raleigh, Wake County, NC c. 1939, PhC.68.1.196.1-5; Carolina Power and Light
- Interurban Line Trolley, Lexington, Kentucky Vicinity (Previously "Trolley to Bloomsbury Park c. 1913). An interurban trolley car is seen traveling away from camera beside a dirt road between two corn fields. This photo was previously identified as "Trolley to Bloomsbury Park, Raleigh, NC c. 1913" However, it is thought to have been taken between Paris and Lexington, Kentucky and used by CP&L as a reference for possible plans to use this type of trolley in Raleigh or the surrounding area. Reference material is included with file. c. 1909, PhC.68.1.197.1-2; Carolina Power and Light
- Raleigh, NC, Intersection of Fairview and Oberlin Roads c. 1940. Intersection of Oberlin and Fairview Roads in Raleigh, NC looking southeast. Fire Station No. 6 can be seen along with Hayes Barton Grocerteria. Automobiles can be seen parked on the sides of the streets. Raleigh, Wake County, NC c.1940, PhC.68.1.198.1-2; Carolina Power and Light
- Raleigh, NC, Professional Building c. 1925. Exterior view of the Professional Building on the corner of Hargett and McDowell Streets in Raleigh, NC. Southern School Supply is seen on the right side (McDowell) and the Biblical Recorder building is seen on left side (Hargett). Two men are seen standing near the entrance. Appears to have been taken just after completion. Raleigh, Wake County, NC c. 1925, PhC.68.1.199; Carolina Power and Light